Guide to the Robin Morgan Papers, 1940s-2010 and undated, bulk 1970-2000
Robin Morgan papers 1940s-2010 and undated, bulk 1970-2000
- Accession (2009-0069), 1993-2006, (3 boxes)
  Addition (2009-0069) (900 items; 1.5 lin. ft.; 1993-2006) includes Morgan's files on sexual trafficking (2000); a master copy and page proofs of The Burning Time (2005-2006); and email printouts of responses to Letters from Ground Zero, which went viral on the Internet following Sept. 11, 2001.
  - Trafficking, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Conflitto e liberta femminile, Spring 1993
  - The Burning Time drafts and master copy, 2005-2006
  - Sept. 11, 2001
  - Ghosts responses (Box 2)
  - Responses to Letters from Ground Zero
  - Loose correspondence
  - Loose correspondence (Box 3)
- Accession (2010-0176), 1947-2010, (19 boxes)
  Accession (2010-0176) (18,450 items; 24.6 lin. ft.; dated 1947-2010) includes Morgan's travel files, correspondence, Ms. editorial files, and materials from her research and publications. General correspondence (dating 1996-2009) consists of email printouts and letters detailing Morgan's activities with various projects, conferences, and boards, including Equality Now and the February Sisters. It also includes her thoughts on the 2008 presidential election, including a re-written version of Goodbye to All That discussing the Hillary Clinton campaign.
  The Ms. files (dating 2002-2010) include global dispatches, correspondence, and cover story interviews by Morgan of Madeleine Albright and Jane Fonda. This section also contains files from the Ms. search for editor-in-chief.
  A large portion of the accession relates to Morgan's writings, poetry, and published books. These materials consist of drafts, correspondence with publishers, publicity and press, reader reactions, reviews of her work, and rights permissions. Works represented include Monster, which included the poem Arraignment; The Mysteries, a play; Upstairs in the Garden; Going Too Far; The Anatomy of Freedom; The Witch Tales; Sisterhood is Forever; and other poems and articles. The majority of the Sisterhood is Forever materials are contributor files, including women like Gloria Steinem, Eleanor Smeal, Eve Ensler, Rep. Eleanor Holmes Norton, and many others.
  Also represented are supporting materials, mainly clippings and other miscellaneous items, from Morgan's childhood, adolescence, and early adulthood that she used for writing her Memoirs. These clippings include coverage of her activities as a child star on the television show Mama, as well as her other performances, radio and television shows, and modelling engagements. Morgan's early activities in the women's liberation movement are also represented in these clippings, such as her protesting the Miss America competition in 1969 and coverage of her book, Sisterhood Is Powerful. The original clippings are extremely fragile and may require Technical Services intervention.
  Other materials in the accession include various research and project files, many supporting Morgan's activities or writings. For example, there is a series of folders on clitoredectomy and female genital mutilation, culminating in a draft prepared by Morgan and Gloria Steinem of an article published in the 1970s. Materials from the Women's Media Center are closed due to restrictions. There is also a significant amount of audiovisual material, including film, VHS, reel-to-reel audio, and DVDs. These will require reformatting prior to use by researchers.
  - Travel, 1959-2001 (Box 1)
    - London, Paris, Florence, 1959 (2 folders)
    - UN women's conferences, Copenhagen and Oslo, 1980-1981 (2 folders)
    - Mexico, 1981
    - UN panel, Vienna, 1982
    - London Book Fair, 1984
    - Meetings with Greek women, Greece, 1984
    - Holiday, St. Thomas, 1984-1985
    - CEDAW meetings, Brazil, 1987
    - Japan, 1988
    - Occupied Territories, 1989
    - Asia Foundation work with women, Nepal, 1994 (4 folders)
    - UN women's conference, Beijing, 1995 (3 folders)
    - General clippings, China, 1995
    - Book tour, Italy, 1996
    - Nepal, 1997
    - Women's conference, Basque Country, Spain, 1998
    - Book tour, Italy, 1998
    - Book tour, Italy, 2001
  - Ms. materials (Box 2)
    - Search for editor-in-chief, 2002 (2 folders)
    - Interim/summer issues, 2002 (9 folders)
    - Correspondence, 2003 (3 folders)
    - Columns, 2003 (2 folders)
    - Correspondence, 2004
    - Los Angeles trip, 2004
    - Columns, 2004
    - Global/international, 2004 (2 folders)
    - International rejects, 2004 (3 folders)
    - Dispatches and networking, Winter 2004
    - Albright interview, 2003-2004 (Box 3)
    - News, Winter 2004
    - Spring 2005
    - Global news, Spring 2005
    - Summer 2005
    - Dispatches, Summer 2005
    - Jane Fonda cover story, 2005
    - Global, Fall 2005
    - Dispatches, Fall 2005
    - 2005 (2 folders)
    - Global news, Winter 2005-2006
    - Dispatches, Winter 2005-2006
    - Dispatches, Spring 2006
    - Global news, Spring 2006
    - Global, Summer 2006
    - Global, Fall 2006
    - Winter 2006-2007
    - Global, Spring 2007
    - Global, Summer 2007
    - Fall 2007 (Box 4)
    - Winter 2008
    - Summer 2008
    - Global, Fall 2008
    - Winter 2008-2009
    - Global, Spring 2009
    - Summer 2009
    - Global, Fall 2009
    - Winter 2010 (2 folders)
    - Spring 2010
    - Summer 2010
    - Fall 2010
  - Women's Radio Network, 2005 (2 folders)
  - University of Denver, 2002-2005 (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - General correspondence, 1986-2009
    - Bella Abzug, 1986
    - 1996
    - 1999 (2 folders)
    - 2000 (3 folders)
    - 2001 (5 folders)
    - 2001-2002
    - 2002 (4 folders)
    - 2002 (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Equality Now, 2002
    - February Sisters, 2002
    - 2003 (6 folders)
    - 2004
    - Equality Now, 2004
    - 2005
    - 2005 (3 folders) (Box 7)
    - 2006 (4 folders)
    - 2007 (4 folders)
    - 2008 (3 folders)
    - 2009
  - Beijing UN Conference piece, 1995 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence re: Women's Studies Encyclopedia, 1992-2000
  - Global Fund for Women, 1990-1999 (4 folders)
  - Feminist Press Board, 1996-1998
  - Rat, women's takeover issue, February 1970
    Includes Goodbye to All That (number 1).
  - Bella Abzug's death and memorial service file, 1998
  - Bella Awards copy, 2001
  - Bella Book (The Bella Project), 2004
  - Gil Morgenstern gigs, 2008-2009
  - Chai Ling Ms. interview (re: Tiananmen Square), 1989-1990
  - BBC Byline, 1990-1991
  - Song lyrics, undated
  - Monster files, 1968-1979
    Materials from Morgan's first book of poetry (1972). Includes draft, submissions, correspondence, the Feminist Art Journal and other feminist editions, reactions, and reviews. Contains discussion of the Ted Hughes/Sylvia Plath controversy.
  - Vietnamese poetry translations, 1967-1968 (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Poems: translations, 1981
  - Poems set to music, 1967-1975
  - The Mysteries
  - Upstairs in the Garden, 1989-1991 (7 folders)
    Literary magazine published poems, contracts, discarded poems, production, reviews, and reactions.
  - Poems: magazine submissions and publications, 1974-1981 (3 folders)
  - A Garden Journal, 2000-2002 (3 folders)
  - Essays and articles, 1977 (2 folders)
  - The Handmaiden of the Holy Man, 2003
  - Fundamentalisms re: religions, 1996-1997 (8 folders)
  - Going Too Far, 1969-1976 (4 folders) (Box 10)
    Includes drafts, production materials, correspondence, etc.
  - Monster and Going Too Far contracts and royalty statements, 1971-1980
  - Permissions: articles and poems, 1976-1994 (5 folders)
  - Infringements and plagiarisms, 1973-1981
  - The Witch Tales drafts, undated (3 folders)
  - The Anatomy of Freedom, 1981-1986 (9 folders)
    Manuscripts, drafts, publication, reviews, and reactions.
  - The Anatomy of Freedom publication rights, 1982-1999 (Box 11)
  - Depth Perception, 1982
  - The Word of a Woman, 1990s (10 folders)
  - Dry Your Smile, 1987-1988
  - Memoir materials
    Press coverage and other materials from Morgan's entertainment career (as a child in the 1950s), her activism during the Women's Liberation movement (1970s-present), and her writings and public events. Most of the newspaper clippings are extremely fragile and may require preservation photocopies to be made before use. Please handle with care.
    - Childhood clippings and correspondence, 1947-1950
    - Childhood scrapbook pages, 1947-1950
    - Mama clippings and press (3 folders)
    - Television shows, books, and miscellaneous clippings, 1951-1980
    - Teen years clippings
    - Schoolwork
    - Women's Liberation clippings, 1960s-1970s (2 folders)
      Including Miss America coverage, Sisterhood is Powerful, and interviews with Morgan.
    - General press clippings, 1980s-1990s
  - Memoir materials: Women's Liberation movement clippings, 1960s-1970s (2 folders) (Box 12)
  - Clitoredectomy (female genital mutilation) files, 1970s (4 folders)
    Includes drafts from piece on female circumcision by Gloria Steinem and Robin Morgan.
  - Katharine Hepburn research file, 1981 and undated
  - Poems: translations, 1981
  - Audiovisual materials (Box 13)
    Consists of 10 VHS tapes, 9 audio cassette tapes, 16 reel-to-reels, 1 film reel, and 2 DVDs. Includes video clips from Morgan's child modeling and clips and reviews of her television shows, including Mama and other plays. Audio tapes include Their Own Country (a verse play), Church of the Ascension, Fifth Avenue, New York, 1961; Mike Wallace interview with Morgan; and her teenage trip abroad in the 1950s. Audio cassettes include tapes of Morgan's interview with Madeleine Albright and her leading the women's takeover of the Phil Donahue Show. Videotapes and DVDs include the Bella Abzug memorial service, with speakers Morgan, Gloria Steinem, Jane Fonda, Shirley Maclaine, Marlo Thomas, etc.; Morgan's interview on Charlie Rose; film of the first Miss America Pageant protest, 1968; and Morgan's participation on various panels.
  - Sisterhood is Forever files, 2000-2003 (Box 14)
    - Kathy Boudin and Roslyn Smith correspondence (4 folders)
    - General correspondence, 2001
    - Publishing/contributor files, A-B, 2001-2003
      - Bravo, Ellen
      - Appel-Bronstein, Ellen
      - Angier, Natalie
      - Adler, Margot
      - Adams, Carol J.
      - Acosta-Belén, Edna, and Christine E. Bose
    - Events (5 folders)
    - First serial, 2002-2003
    - Revised versions
    - Bids and contracts
    - Conference, 2002
    - Book and manuscript, 2003
    - Random House correspondence, 2002
    - Contributor contracts, Random House (2 folders)
    - WSP contracts
    - Reviews, 2003 (2 folders)
    - Reactions, 2003
    - Foreign rights, 2002-2003
    - Film/television rights, 2004
    - Promotion, 2002-2003 (2 folders)
    - Production, 2002 (2 folders)
    - Publishing/contributor files, C-M, 2001-2003 (Box 15)
      - Carter, Vednita
      - Chavkin, Wendy
      - Crenshaw, Kimberlé (2 folders)
      - DiPerna, Paula
      - Drusine, Helen
      - Dworkin, Andrea
      - Ensler, Eve
      - Findlen, Barbara
      - Funiciello, Theresa
      - Guy-Sheftall, Beverly
      - Gilligan, Carol
      - Gould, Sara K.
      - Guerilla Girls
      - Hanna, Kathleen
      - Hershey, Laura
      - Hill, Anita
      - Howe, Florence
      - Hughes, Donna
      - Jay, Karla
      - Jemison, Mae C.
      - Jenkins, Carol
      - Kennedy, Claudia
      - Kessler-Harris, Alice
      - Kidwell, Clara Sue
      - Kissling, Frances
      - Levine, Suzanne Braun
      - Macdonald, Barbara
      - MacKinnon, Catherine
      - Martin, Jane Roland
      - Michals, Debra
      - Morgan, Robin (3 folders)
    - Publishing/contributor files, N-Z, 2001-2003 (Box 16)
      - Neuwirth, Jessica
      - New Moon Girls
      - Norsigian, Judy (OBOS)
      - Norton, Eleanor Holmes
      - Paley, Grace
      - Richards, Amy, and Marianne Schnall
      - Richards, Cecile
      - Sachs, Carolyn
      - Schroeder, Pat
      - Smeal, Eleanor
      - Steinem, Gloria
      - Thom, Mary (2 folders)
      - Victoria, Jasmine
      - Wattleton, Faye
      - Wilson, Marie
      - Zia, Helen
  - Women's Media Center files (Box 17-19)
    These boxes are CLOSED due to RESTRICTIONS.